＜無限に広がる大宇宙｡
永遠に終わることはない｡
＜死にいく星 生まれくる星｡
＜ それは ときに
人類の想像を上回る➡
生命から生命へと受け継がれる
大宇宙の息吹は➡
そこには さまざまな生命が
満ち溢れている＞
恐ろしい危機を
呼び寄せることとなる＞
解明されつくすことのない
大宇宙の神秘…＞
♪♪～
Please turn on the lights and keep your distance from the television when watching Gintama. You got thaaaat?!
The Universe, vast and limitless, is filled with many life forms.
As one star dies, another gives birth.
The breath of the vast Universe is passed on from one life to another.
A never-ending cycle.
The mysteries of the vast Universe can never be completely revealed.
At times, it can even bring upon horrific dangers that defy the human imagination.
["Beware of Food You Pick Up Off the Ground"]
Hmm... He's not eating again.
(神楽)う～ん…
また 食べてないｱﾙ｡
Gin, Sadaharu doesn't have an appetite lately.
(神楽)銀ちゃん…
定春 この頃 また 食欲ないね｡
この２日 ろくに
ご飯 食べてないよ｡
He's hardly eaten anything for two days.
具合が悪いのかもしれないね｡
He might not be feeling well.
(銀時)ﾀﾞｲｴｯﾄでも
してんじゃねえの｡
Maybe he's just on a diet.
これくらいの年ごろの ｵｽはな
ﾑﾀﾞに そういうこと するんだよ｡
Males his age do silly things like that just so they can get girls.
女に ﾓﾃたくて｡
定春は そんなん違うね！ 硬派ｱﾙ｡
Sadaharu's not like that. He's the stoic type.
んなこと いって 前も どっかの
ﾒｽ犬に発情してただろうが｡
The last time you said that, he was aroused over some female dog, remember?
[Odd Jobs Gin]
(新八)でも ふだん あれだけ
食べてるだけに 心配ですね｡
But he usually eats a lot. I'm worried.
病院 連れてったほうが
いいかもしれないですよ｡
Maybe we should take him to the hospital.
Leave him alone.
ほっとけよ｡ 硬派なんだから
塩 ふって なめときゃ 治るよ｡
He's tough. Sprinkle some salt for him to lick and he'll recover.
[Kabukicho Animal Hospital]
(医者)う～ん…
胃に 影が見えますね｡
It seems there's a shadow in his stomach.
影!? 何ｱﾙか？ それ｡
Shadow? Is it something terrible?
どこかの回し者ｱﾙか？
徳川の… いや 柳生の影ｱﾙか？
Who's behind this?
Is it a shadow ninja, of the Tokugawa...or the Yagyu?
No, not Tokugawa shadows. There's something in his stomach.
(医者)いや
徳川の忍とかじゃなくて➡
胃に何かが…｡
Does he have an illness?!
何かって 病気ｱﾙか!?
定春 病気ｱﾙか!? 治るｱﾙか!?
Is Sadaharu sick?!
Will he recover?!
おい！ 治るんだろうな？
(医者)落ち着いてください！
He will recover, won't he?!
Calm down.
(医者)あの 病気とかじゃなくてね
胃に異物がね｡
He's not sick. There's a foreign object in his stomach.
(神楽)異物？
(医者)えぇ｡
Foreign object?
Yes. Did you make Sadaharu eat anything odd?
皆さん 定春君に 何か 変なもの
食べさせませんでした？
Huh? We haven't fed him anything except basic dog food.
えっ？ 基本 ﾄﾞｯｸﾞﾌｰﾄﾞしか
食べさせてませんよ｡
(医者)あぁ じゃあ 散歩中に➡
I see.
Then he probably ate something off the ground when you took him for a walk.
拾い食いとかしてたんだね
たぶん｡
Dogs put unbelievable things in their mouths when their owners aren't looking.
犬は 飼い主の知らないところで➡
信じられないものとか
口にしたりしてますから｡
Especially since Sadaharu is a large breed, anything can go in.
特に 定春君は大きいから
なんでも入るでしょ｡
You need to be careful.
気をつけないとね｡
So, this is the shadow.
あぁ… これが
その影なんですけどもね｡
これ… なんですかね？
よく わからないけども…｡
What could this be? I can't really tell.
とりあえず 吐かせますんで｡
そしたら すぐ治ると思うんで｡
Anyway, I'll get him to vomit it out. That'll make him better in no time.
No! Never mind!
いや！ いいです やっぱ!!
(医者)えっ!? なんで？
Huh? Why?
No, it's because, you know!
いや あの… あれ
吐かせるくらいだったら➡
If all we have to do it make him vomit, we can do it ourselves.
ﾎﾞｸたちでも あれなんで
か… 帰ります！
We're...going home.
(医者)いや でも 吐かせるとき
ﾉﾄﾞ 詰まらせたら 大変なんで｡
No, if it gets stuck in his throat as he vomits it out, it could be trouble.
それに 場合によっては お腹
切らないと ﾀﾞﾒかもしれないんで｡
And depending on the situation, he might require surgery.
We can manage!
大丈夫です!! 腹 切るなら
得意ですから ﾎﾞｸら｡ 侍ですから！
We're good at slitting our bellies. We're samurai, you know.
(医者)いや ｱﾝﾀらじゃなくて｡
いや ﾎﾝﾄ 大丈夫ですから！
No, not yours.
No, really, it's all right. Just let us go. Don't call the police.
勘弁してください 警察だけは！
(医者)警察？
The police?
何やってんだ!? 早く来い 定春！
お前 とっ捕まりたいのか!!
What're you doing? Hurry and come with us, Sadaharu!
Do you want to be caught?
ｼｪｰｯ！
だぁ～！ 口からなんか出てきた!!
It's coming out of his mouth!
銀さん 口から出てます！
戻せ！
Gin, from his mouth.
Push it back in!
Sadaharu, open wide.
定春 あ～ん！
(銀時/新八)あぁ～！
For now, there doesn't seem to be anything else.
とりあえず 他には
何もなかったみたいｱﾙ｡
でも 大事をとって 今日は
病院に泊まったほうがいいって｡
But to be safe, they say he should stay overnight at the hospital.
I see.
あぁ そう…｡
I'm worried, so is it okay if I stay with Sadaharu overnight?
私 心配だから 定春と一緒に
泊まっていいｱﾙか？
Oh, okay.
あぁ そう…｡
(神楽)なんで あんなに
疲れてるｱﾙか？
Why're they so tired?
(桂)ん!? ﾘｰﾀﾞｰではないか｡
If it isn't Leader...
(神楽)あれ？ ﾂﾞﾗ！
(桂)ﾂﾞﾗじゃない 桂だ｡
Huh? Zura?
Not Zura. Katsura.
What're you doing here?
どうした？ こんな所で｡ まさか
定春殿の具合でも悪いのか？
Don't tell me Sir Sadaharu is not well?
Not as sick as your mind. Don't worry.
(神楽)お前の
頭の具合ほどじゃないｱﾙ｡
大丈夫ね｡
そうか それはよかった｡
I see, I'm glad to hear that.
Zura, what brings you here?
(神楽)ﾂﾞﾗ… お前は どうしたね？
普通の病院じゃ➡
Did you come to an animal hospital because regular hospitals won't touch you?
手がつけられなくて
動物病院行きｱﾙか？
いや ちと
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽの元気がないのでな｡
No, Elizabeth's been lacking energy.
診てもらおうと思って来たんだが
ﾚﾝﾄｹﾞﾝに ｲﾔな影が映ってな｡
I came here hoping to have her looked at.
The X-rays showed a disturbing shadow.
(神楽)いや
それ ただの おっさんｱﾙ｡
No, it's just an old man.
Seems she ate something that looked like an old man off the ground during our walk.
(桂)どうやら散歩中に➡
何か おっさん的なものを
拾い食いしたらしい｡
(神楽)いや おっさん
拾ってきたのは お前だろ｡
No, you're the one who picked up the old man, I bet.
So that's why she'll be having an operation to remove the old man soon.
そういうことでな➡
近日 おっさんを摘出する
ｵﾍﾟをすることになった｡
Taking out the old man means the whole body.
おっさん摘出って
それ 本体だろが｡
It's no wonder I thought she was behaving strangely.
今まで どおりでおかしいと
思っていたんだ｡
近くに寄ったら
加齢臭とかするし｡
When I go near her, she smells of aging body odor.
ｵｲ 目 背けてんじゃねえぞ｡
Hey, don't deny the truth.
お前の飼ってるのは
ただの おっさんなんだっつうの｡
What you were keeping as a pet is just an old man.
(桂)まぁ お互い➡
Well,
it's a good thing neither was life-threatening.
命に関わるようなことでなくて
よかったではないか｡
(神楽)お前は 関わってるだろう｡
Yours is threatened.
After all, you always want to have your pet smiling at your side.
(桂)やはり
ﾍﾟｯﾄには いつまでも隣で➡
微笑んでいてほしいものだからな｡
確かに そうｱﾙな｡
(定春)ﾜﾝ！
That's true.
(医者)できるだけ
手は つくしたんですが➡
I did everything I could, but he was, after all, an old dog.
まぁ なにぶん 老犬なもので｡
これ以上は 体の方が
治療に耐えられないかと…｡
I don't think his body can withstand any more treatment.
I see.
(三郎)そうですか…｡
Kintaro...looks like I won't be able to take him to my Dad.
金太郎… 親父には
会わせてやれそうにねえな｡
Is your Father's condition that bad?
(医者)悪いんですか
おじいさまの容態…｡
Yes. Seems he's not going to make it, either.
(三郎)ええ…
実は 向こうもﾀﾞﾒそうで｡
Imagine a pet dog and its owner falling ill at the same time.
まさか 飼い主と飼い犬
同時に倒れちまうなんざ｡
(医者)そうですか…
おじいさま 本当に➡
I see. Your father was really fond of Kintaro.
金太郎君のこと
かわいがってましたもんね｡
(三郎)じじいに じじ犬｡
お互い いろんなもんなくして➡
An old man and his old dog.
They both lost many things, until all that was left at the end was their friendship.
最後に残った
ﾀﾞﾁ公みてえなもんでしたから｡
Those fools, are they planning to die together as well?
ﾊﾞｶたれどもめ おっ死ぬときまで
一緒にいこうってんですかね｡
Doctor, I've got to go see my Dad.
先生 ｵﾚは親父の方に
行かなきゃならねえ｡
金太郎のこと お願えします｡
どうか最期は➡
Please look after Kintaro.
Please see to it that he passes on peacefully.
穏やかにいけるように
してやってくだせえ｡
すまねえ… 金太郎｡
さよならは 言わねえよ｡
Sorry... Kintaro, I won't say good-bye.
…ありがとな｡
Thanks.
♪♪～
眠れないﾈ｡
I can't fall asleep.
ｲﾀﾀ… ん？
じゃまなとこに寝てるｱﾙか｡
Zura?
What, are you trying to get in my way by sleeping there?
ん いや…｡
Huh? No.
ちょっと寝苦しかったものでな｡
I was having a bit of trouble falling asleep.
ここは 風通しがよくて
寝やすそうだ｡
Here there's a breeze and it seemed like a good place to sleep.
ほんとｱﾙ 私も ここにしよ｡
That's true. I'll crash here, too.
(猫たちの鳴き声)
♪♪～
(神楽)本当は
私たちなんかじゃなくて➡
I'm sure he wanted his master to be at his side when he dies, not us.
ご主人さまに 死に水を
とってもらいたかっただろうな｡
(桂)どうだかな｡
Who knows?
I heard it from the doctor.
医者から聞いた｡
It's almost a miracle that he's still alive despite being ravaged to such an extent by disease.
こんな病魔に蝕まれながらも
生きているのは➡
奇跡に等しいと｡
この犬 一人暮らしの
おじいさんを➡
This animal is apparently a loyal dog that supported his master who lived alone for all these years.
ずっと支えていた
忠犬だったらしい｡
妻が死んだあとも
子供たちを寄せつけず➡
He nestled up next to a stubborn old man
一人で暮らしていた
頑固じいさんに寄り添って➡
who wouldn't even have anything to do with his own children after his wife died.
ずっと見守り続けていたんだ｡
こんな ﾎﾞﾛﾎﾞﾛになるまで｡
He hung on until he was this ragged.
おじいさんが倒れると同時に➡
When the old man collapsed,
役目を終えたように
ﾊﾟﾀﾘと倒れたらしい｡
it seems he just flopped down as if to say his job had ended.
いや ひょっとして
あの世にまで➡
No, maybe he is trying to follow his master into the afterlife.
つき従っていこうと
しているのかもな｡
だとしたら これで
本望なのかもしれんよ｡
If that's the case, then maybe this is what he wanted.  This tiny samurai.
この小さな侍も…｡
ﾂﾞﾗ そんなんだから お前は➡
Zura, that's why they send you to the animal hospital.
動物病院送りにされるね｡
(桂)何？
What?
決めたｱﾙ！ 私
やっぱり このこを➡
I've made up my mind.
I'm going to let this dog see the old man, after all.
じいさんに会わせてあげるね！
はぁ？
待て ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ 何を言ってるんだ！
Wait, Leader. What're you talking about?
こんな状態の犬を
連れだすつもりか!?
You plan to take a dog in this condition with you?
待たないｱﾙ！ こんなところで
一人ぼっちで死んで➡
It can't wait.
You're the only ones who'd be happy that he died
美談にされて それで喜ぶのは
お前らだけｱﾙ！
all by himself in a place like this and became a noble tale.
忘れたのか!? 会わすにも➡
Have you forgotten?
We can try to get them together, but the old man is on the brink of death himself.
肝心のおじいさんさえも
すでに死の淵にあるんだぞ！
だからこそ むこうも会いたいと
思ってるに違いないｱﾙ！
That's why I'm sure he's hoping to see each other, too.
会いたいも何も
もはや意識などないではないか！
Hope to see him? He's already lost consciousness.
息をするだけで精一杯なんだぞ｡
考える力など もはやない！
It's all he can do just to breathe.
He has no strength left.
(桂)医者も言っていただろう｡
The doctor said so himself.
ﾑﾀﾞに苦しめるより
穏やかに死なせてや…｡
Instead of needlessly making him suffer, let him peacefully...
(桂)お… お前｡
You...you're...
そんな…
そんなになってまで お前…｡
Does it...mean that much to you?
(神楽)犬ｺﾛが ﾎﾞﾛﾎﾞﾛになって
のたうち回りながらも➡
When a dog is ragged, and writhes in agony, desperately trying live a long life,
必死に長生きして➡
the reason why he won't leave his master's side is obvious.
それでも ずっと主人のそばを
離れない理由なんて決まってるｱﾙ｡
ずっと そばにいたかったからに
決まってるｱﾙ…｡
It's because he wants to stay at his master's side forever.
離れたくなかったからに
決まってるｱﾙ！
It's obviously because he doesn't want to leave.
だったら 最後に このこに
してやれることは一つね！
Then there's just one final thing we can do for this dog.
I see.
そうか… 小さな侍殿➡
Little Mr. Samurai, I have underestimated you.
ｵﾚは おぬしを
見くびっていたようだ｡
本物の侍とは
信念に殉ずるのではなく➡
A true samurai does not die for his beliefs. He lives for his beliefs, doesn't he?
信念に生きるものであったな｡
よし！ いざ
おじいさんのもとへいく…｡
Okay!
Let's head to where the old man is.
(金太郎)わけねえだろ！
Like hell I will!
忌々しい じじいに
封印され 苦節18年！
After eighteen years of suffering while sealed in by that despicable old man, finally...
ついに…
ついに鎖は腐り落ちた！
Finally, the chains have rotted off!
恐怖の大王復活のときが
きたのだ… ﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊ！
The time for the resurrection of the King of Terror has come.
地球は もう おし… ｺﾞﾎｯ！
Earth has come to an...
(金太郎)やべえ… 苦しい！
救急車！ 救急車 呼んで！
Uh-oh, it hurts... Call an ambulance!
[18 Years Prior]
We go back in time eighteen years.
＜無限に広がる
大宇宙の彼方から➡
From beyond the far reaches of the vast Universe,
恐るべき災いの光が
地球へと迫りつつあった＞
a frightful beam bringing disaster is approaching Earth.
＜寄生腫Ｘ｡ それは
星喰と恐れられる存在であった＞
Parasite X.
Feared as the "Planet Eater."
＜Ｘは 無数に分裂し
星へと降り注ぐ｡
X splits into infinite beams, raining down on the planet.
あらゆる生物に寄生し
その中枢を支配するとともに➡
Parasitically attaching to all life forms,
it controls the central nervous system
宿主の遺伝子を操作し
超進化をとげ➡
and manipulates its hosts' genes, evolving incredibly quickly,
またたくまに強力な
侵略集団を作り上げる｡
to create a powerful invasion force in the blink of an eye.
Ｘに侵略された星は
どれも巨大な顎に➡
Every planet invaded by X is left with a huge scar, as though torn off by a huge jaw.
食いちぎられたような
大きな傷跡を残した｡
星喰と呼ばれる由縁である＞
This is how they got the name "Planet Eaters."
(Ｘ)地球… なかなか
美しい星ではないか｡
Earth.  Looks like quite a lovely planet.
あの美しい星に 我が牙を➡
I tremble with excitement when I think of sinking my fangs into such a juicy planet.
突き立てることを思うと
ｿﾞｸｿﾞｸするわ｡
ﾌﾌﾌ… さて 今回は➡
So, which creature should I attach myself to this time?
いったい どんな生物に
とりついてやろうか｡
ちょろそうだから
今回は目をつぶっていくか｡
Looks easy, so this time, I'll go with my eyes closed.
まあ 何がきても
大方 大丈夫だろう… ﾜﾊﾊﾊ！
Whatever happens, I'll probably be fine.
母ちゃんの腹の中で
死にかけてた雑種犬に入ってた！
I've entered a mongrel that almost died in its mother's womb.
Idiot! I'm an idiot!
(金太郎)ﾊﾞｶ！ ｵﾚのﾊﾞｶ！
なんで調子にのるかなぁ！
Why did I get so carried away like that!
なんで 目なんか つぶるかな!?
With my eyes closed!
山登りは 八合目からが本番だって
先輩にも言われてたのに｡
Even my senpai told me the real climb begins just before the summit.
(金太郎)おかげで そこから18年間
犬小屋に封印され➡
As a result, I was cooped up in a dog house for eighteen years,
地球征服にも着手できない
平和な日々｡
spending peaceful days without being able to start on world conquest.
それでも なんとかしようと
努力したさ！
Even then, though, I tried so hard.
遺伝子いじくったりしたさ！
進化しようとしたさ！
Fiddling around with the genes and such, you know?
I tried to evolve, you know?!
でも 結局 逆上がりが
できるようになっただけ｡
But in the end,
all I could do was learn to do the front raise on a bar!
最後の手段で
じいさんの寿命を待ち➡
As a final measure, I waited for the old man to die,
ついに解放されたと思ったら…｡
but just when I thought I was finally free...
ｵﾚも寿命だった｡
My life reached its limit, as well.
How cruel!
ひでぇよ！ 世の中 神も
恐怖の大王もありゃしねえよ｡
Is there no god or King of Terror in this world?!
まだ 逆上がりしか
してないんだよ｡
All I've ever done is a front raise.
ｸﾞﾗｲﾀﾞｰも覚えてないんだよ
ｵﾚの人生を返してくれ！
I haven't even learned the glider yet!
Give me back my life!
要するに お前
地球征服しようとして失敗して➡
So what happened is, you attempted to take over the Earth, but failed,
ずっと
じいさんに飼われてたｱﾙか｡
and you were kept as the old man's pet this whole time?
じゃあ
必至に長生きしてたのも➡
Then the reason you desperately tried to live a long life
じいさんのそばに いたいとか
支えたいとかじゃなくて…｡
wasn't because you wanted to stay by the old man's side and support him, but...
地球征服だよ｡
...to conquer the Earth.
I waited vigilantly for the old man to die so I'd be freed from that stupid doghouse.
じいさんが死んで
犬小屋から解放されるのを➡
虎視眈々と待ってたんだ｡
(神楽)すみませ～ん｡
(ｳｴｲﾄﾚｽ)はい｡
Excuse me.
Yes?
この天人を ﾚﾝｼﾞでﾁﾝして
ﾎｯﾄﾄﾞｯｸﾞにしてください｡
Nuke this Amanto in the microwave and make a hot dog out of him.
(金太郎)ｲﾔ～!!
ｷｬｯ！
(神楽)私 もうｲﾔｱﾙ｡
Nooo!
I'm sick of this.
ﾓﾁﾍﾞｰｼｮﾝ落ちたね 帰るｱﾙ｡
(桂)まぁ 待て ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ｡
My motivation's down. I'm going home.
Now, wait, Leader.
確かに この犬に
何かしてやる価値はない｡
It's true there's nothing to be gained by helping this dog.
しかし おじいさんは
こんな犬でも➡
But I'm sure the old man wants to see this dog, despite what it is.
会いたがっているに違いない｡
乗りかかった船だ
会わせてやってもﾊﾞﾁは当たらんぞ｡
We should finish what we started.
What've we got to lose by letting them see each other?
星喰 ｷｻﾏも 今まで
散々 悪行を働いてきたんだ｡
Planet Eater...
You've done a whole lot of evil. At least before you die...
最後くらい…｡
(猫)ついに 見つけたぞ！
I've finally found you!
なんだ!?
What's going on?
[18 Years Prior]
We go back in time eighteen years.
＜無限に広がる
大宇宙の彼方から➡
From beyond the far reaches of the vast Universe,
神々しき暁光が
地球へと迫りつつあった＞
an intense celestial light is approaching Earth.
＜寄生腫Ｚ それは
星吐と崇められる存在であった＞
Parasite Z, revered as the Planet Pukers.
＜Ｚは 無数に分裂し
星へと降り注ぐ｡
Z splits into infinite beams, raining down on the planet.
Parasitically attaching to any life form,
あらゆる生物に寄生し
なんやかんやで超進化を遂げ➡
星喰を駆逐し 星を救う｡
they evolve incredibly quickly, exterminating the Planet Eaters and saving planets.
いわば 星喰の対抗勢力
正義の味方であった｡
They are, so to speak, the Planet Eaters' counterbalancing force-the allies of good.
Ｚは 星を救うと➡
When Z saves a planet, it leaves covered in the vomit of its host as it is expelled.
寄生していた宿主から
ｹﾞﾛとともに出てきて去るため➡
星中 ｹﾞﾛまみれになった｡
星吐と呼ばれる由縁である＞
This is how they got the name "Planet Pukers."
((Ｚ:地球 こんな美しい星を➡
Earth.
So the Planet Eaters are trying to eat away this beautiful planet.
ﾔﾂら 星喰は
食い荒らそうとしているのか｡
そんなことは 絶対に許さん｡
We must never allow that to happen.
必ず ﾎﾞｸらが この星を護りきり
ｹﾞﾛまみれにしてみせる｡
We will protect this planet without fail and cover it with vomit!
しかし 今回は いったい
どんな生物で対抗しようか｡
But the question is, what animal shall we counter with?
ちょろそうだから
今回は 白目むいていこう｡
Looks easy, so this time, we'll go with our eyes half-opened.
Whatever happens, it'll be fine.
まぁ 何が来ても
大方 大丈夫だろう))
(猫)星喰 最後の１匹
ついに見つけたぞ｡
Planet Eater... I've finally found the last one of you.
(猫)絶対に…
ぶっ殺してやるからな｡
I will...kill you for sure!
何あれ？ また変なのが…｡
What's that? More strange creatures?
あれは 星吐！
(猫)いけ～！
That's...
The Planet Pukers!
Charge!
えぇ～!?
おぉ～！
いや～!!
[Oedo Hospital]
(一郎)そうかい 金太郎のﾔﾂも➡
I see. Poor Kintaro.
ずっと
親父を支えてくれたのに➡
He supported Dad for so long, but I couldn't be there when he dies.
看取ることもしてやれずに
申し訳ないよ｡
(次郎)親父が
こんなときなんだから➡
With Dad in this condition, it can't be helped.
しかたないさ｡ それに➡
Besides, Dad's the one who most wanted to be there when that dog dies.
あの犬を いちばん
看取ってやりたいのは親父だろ｡
あんなに
かわいがっていたんだから｡
He was so fond of him.
(三郎)なに 心配せずとも
あの世で会えるさ｡
Not to worry. They'll meet again in the afterlife.
(一郎)これ 不謹慎だぞ｡
Hey, that's imprudent.
(三郎)兄さんたち
力 入りすぎなんだよ｡
You guys are stressing too much.
看病しっぱなしで疲れただろ
少し休んでくれば？
You're exhausted because you've been tending to Dad all this time.
Why don't you take a break?
親父 しばらく大丈夫そうだし｡
Looks like Dad will be okay for a while.
(次郎)ﾎﾝﾄに大丈夫だろうな？
Are you sure you'll be okay?
大丈夫 大丈夫
ちゃんと見とくから｡
Don't worry, don't worry. I'll keep a close watch.
(一郎)じゃあ 頼むぞ｡
(三郎)はい｡
Okay, I'm counting on you.
Alrighty.
(猫たち)ﾆｬｰｵ!!
(猫たち)ﾆｬｰ!!
(定春)ﾜﾝﾜﾝ！
うわっ！
きゃ～っ！
らちがあかないｱﾙ！
This isn't getting anywhere.
What are they? Why're they attacking us?
何なのだ ﾔﾂらは!?
なぜ 我々を襲う？
星吐… ｵﾚたち星喰を駆逐し
星を護る寄生腫だ｡
Planet Pukers...
They're parasites that drive out Planet Eaters like me and protect planets.
早く 早く逃げてくれ！
Quickly, quickly, get away.
捕まったら ｵﾚは消される！
If they catch me, I'll be eliminated.
I had no idea.
知らなかった｡ まさか古来より➡
I wouldn't have believed that cats and dogs
犬と猫が地球の存亡をかけて
戦いを繰り広げていたとは…｡
battled over the fate of the world since ancient times.
(金太郎)いや 違ぇよ｡
たまたま ｵﾚは犬➡
No, that's not how it is.
It's just coincidence that I parasitically attached myself to a dog, and they attached to cats.
ﾔﾂらは
猫に寄生しちまっただけだよ｡
ｵ… ｵﾚは
いったい どうすればいいんだ？
What should I do?
犬に猫 どちらも捨てがたいぞ｡
Dogs...and cats... Both are difficult to forsake.
どっちも肉球がついてるし
ﾌﾜﾌﾜしてるし｡
They're both cuddly balls of flesh and fluffy soft.
あぁ どうしよう…｡
Oh...what should I do?
どちらの肉球にも
消えてほしくない｡
I don't' want either of them to disappear.
(金太郎)おい！ 聞いてんのかよ!?
Hey, are you even listening?!
よし ｵﾚが和平を申し出てみよう｡
All right, I'll make a peace offering.
同じ肉球同士 話し合えば
わかり合えるはずだ！
They're both cuddly balls of flesh-
if they discuss things, they should reach an understanding.
(金太郎)おい なに悠長なこと
言ってんだよ！ 早く逃げろって！
Hey, why're you wasting time talking. Hurry and run.
聞いてくれ 勇敢なる肉球たちよ！
Listen to me, courageous cuddly balls of flesh.
我々は地球を征服する気など
毛頭ない｡
We have no intention of conquering Earth.
ｷﾐらが手を下さずとも➡
Even without your help, this dog is at the end of his life!
この犬は
まもなく寿命で朽ち果てる！
However, we want to let his owner see him once before he dies.
しかし 死ぬ間際に飼い主に
一目 会わせてやりたいのだ｡
ｷﾐらも同じく肉球 持つ者なら
わかるであろう！
As those who are also of flesh and blood, I'm sure you can understand!
ｵﾚたちは野良だ！
We're strays!
Planet Eater! You came to conquer Earth.
星喰 ﾃﾒｴ！
地球征服しにきといて➡
なに飼われて
のうのうと暮らしてんだ！
What're you doing living a leisurely life as a kept pet?!
怒りあおって どうすんだ！
What's the idea of getting them riled up?
(桂)くっ… 説得失敗か｡
I failed to convince them, huh?
まぁいい
ちょっと肉球に触れたぞ｡
Well, that's okay.  At least I got to touch some cuddly balls of flesh.
(金太郎)なに喜んでんだ！
どんだけ肉球 大好きなんだよ!?
What're you so happy about?!
What is it with you and cuddly balls of flesh?!
しかたない｡ かくなるうえは
ｵﾚがﾔﾂらを引きつける！
We have no choice.
Now that it's come to this, I'll draw them to me.
その間に
ﾘｰﾀﾞｰをおじいさんのもとへ！
During that time, Leader, you go to the old man's place.
ﾂﾞﾗ… そこまで…｡
Zura, you'd do all that?
ﾌｯ！ 愛らしい肉球同士が
争うところなど➡
I don't want to see cuddly balls of flesh fighting among themselves.
見たくないのさ｡
あとは頼んだぞ ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ！ ﾊｯ！
Take care of the rest, Leader!
武士道とは肉球に包まれて
死ぬことと見つけたり！
I have discovered Bushido in a death surrounded by cuddly balls of flesh!
《さぁ 来るがいい 肉球たちよ！
All right, come at me, you cuddly balls of flesh!
その肉球でｵﾚを… ｵﾚを…》
With your cuddly balls of flesh...at me...
(金太郎)普通に無視された～！
They ignored him!
[Special Prizes Stefan Goods!! A chance to win 2 weeks in a row!!]
(三郎)ったく こんなのが続いちゃ
身がもたんよ｡
Good grief...
My body's not gonna last if this keeps on.
親父も死ぬなら死ぬで
さっさと いってくれよな｡
If you're going to die, Dad, hurry up and get on with it. I mean really.
ﾎﾝﾄに もう｡
(おじいさん)ｺﾞﾎｯ！
いかん…｡
This is no good.
散歩の時間じゃ｡
Time for my walk.
[To be continued]
[Tell me! Ginpachi Sensei!]
Tell me! Ginpachi Sensei!
Okay, today, we have a letter from someone a bit unusual. I'll read it now.
It's a question from Amachi Hideaki of Tokyo.
This is about something that happened a while back.
When I saw an ending where Kagura was running along the beach in Summer,
I wondered about something, so I wrote this letter.
If I'm not mistaken, Kagura is an Amanto belonging to the Yato Clan,
who are supposed to be vulnerable to sunlight.
Basically, wasn't it a given that she always uses a parasol?
I draw a lot of manga myself, and often forget to draw in the parasol.
But is it all right to do that?
It bothers me so much, I can't get on with my manuscript.
Okay, here's the straight answer.
Yes, I do remember.
It's the one where the voice actress of Kagura said
"Who is this cute girl who appears in the ending?"
when she first saw it, right?
That certainly was Kagura running energetically under the sun with her skin exposed.
But she's fine.
Huh? Why is she fine, you ask?
Okay.
Actually, that was filmed in studio.
Adults play so dirty, don't they?
はい 今日は ちょっと
珍しい人より お便り頂いたので➡
They explain everything that's not going their way after the fact.
それ読みま～す｡
Well, then, Amachi! Don't worry so much about details.
え～ 東京都
天知 英秋君からの質問｡
Have a manuscript by tomorrow.
｢ちょっと前の話になるのですが➡
[Preview]
Hey, Gintoki!
This one's a multi-part episode, so how about we call it the Bark-Meow arc!
神楽が
夏の海辺を走るｴﾝﾃﾞｨﾝｸﾞを見て➡
ふと疑問を感じたので
お便りしました｡
But the Fuzzy-Wuzzy arc is hard to disregard, too.
But there's the Fluffy-Wuffy arc... Maybe the Cuddly Balls of Flesh arc, after all.
たしか神楽って
夜兎族っていう天人で➡
Don't bother. It'll end next week.
What?!
陽の光が苦手だから➡
The next episode:
基本 いつも日傘さしているって
設定じゃなかったでしたっけ？
"Cat Lovers and Dog Lovers Are Mutually Exclusive"
[To reunite with Kintaro (Planet Eater), the Old Man (Stubborn) makes an implacable comeback.]
確かに ｵﾚも漫画描いてて➡
よく 傘描き忘れたりするんだけど
あれは大丈夫なんですか？
[But the Planet Pukers (Cat) hand of pursuit (Cuddly Balls of Flesh) goes dauntlessly after the Planet Eater (Cuddly Balls of Flesh) to corner him (pinch)!!]
気になって
原稿が全然 先に進みません｣｡
はい ｽﾞﾊﾞﾘお答えしましょう｡
ええ 覚えてますよ｡
なかの人が初めて見たとき…｡
(神楽)誰 このｴﾝﾃﾞｨﾝｸﾞに出てくる
かわいい女の子？
って言っちゃった あれね｡
あぁ 確かに神楽が
元気よく太陽の下➡
肌さらして走っちゃってます｡
でも大丈夫です｡
え？ なんで大丈夫かって？
はい 実はｽﾀｼﾞｵで撮影してました｡
いやぁ 大人って
ﾎﾝﾄ きたないですね｡
都合の悪いことは
全部 後づけで説明です｡
じゃあ天知
細かいことは気にせず➡
明日までに ﾈｰﾑ１本あげなさい！